Hello friends, my name is Abhinav Kumar,
welcome.
Today's video is going to be about how you guys are going to
claim bike insurance. So,
some people had commented on this video
that you guys should tell me, that is, tell me
how to claim bike insurance. Our
bike has met with an accident. How much percentage will we
get, how much time will it take and what not.
Whatever questions you have in your mind, all of that is going to be
cleared in this video. So
let's start the video, my Vinod
Kumar and welcome all of you to your own YouTube channel.
Today the video is being
made after 15 days, after 15 or 20 days
on the channel. Before this, I was missing for a long time, so I will
also tell you the reason for my absence
in this very video. In the last, you might have
understood a little by looking at the background etc. So,
due to this, I was missing for a bit, so the
video was not being uploaded for 15 days. So,
now I will try to make the videos almost regular. So,
in today's video, I am going to
tell you
how you can clean your insurance. Like,
your bike has met with an accident and
your bike is in a lot of damage, which this  If
something has happened to it, then
how will you people make an insurance claim for
it? For that, I am going to tell you everything in detail in this video. So, first of all,
when your bike breaks down, you have to
take your bike to the agency. When
you take it to the agency, after going there,
you will be asked for some two remarks, which if it is in
your name, then it is fine, that is, if you are
riding the bike in someone else's name, that is, in your father's name, and you yourself are driving the bike, then you will have to take everything like father's Aadhar
card, RC and driving license etc. I will
probably tell you the documents in it and I will
also show you the list there, so the first
document in it will be your RC, the
second is the insurance paper of the bike, the
third is a
cancelled cheque, the fourth is your Aadhar card and the
fifth is the PAN card and there are one or two
more remarks, I will highlight them in the list here,
you will need those documents, so in
total, you will need 56 five
documents, after that your
vehicle's paper is prepared, the
time file of your vehicle is prepared for you  Whichever
insurance company you go to, the
file is prepared and after the file is prepared, the
process is done for you.
Whichever bank has your
insurance through whichever company the
insurance is kept, the process is done there.
Just one or two days after the process, you will have to leave your bike
at the agency itself.
Your bike will come from
there, that is, a complete inspection will be done from
all sides to see how strong it is and how much it is
damaged. After doing that, you will get
your vehicle further by completing the papers and will you get
insurance or not. After
completing everything, your vehicle is
repaired and it takes about 2 or 3 days for repair and also it may take
10 or 12 days. Different companies have different
processes, like HDFC and
ICICI, the claim processor, it may take
10 or 12 days for your bike to get
repaired. So now I want to tell you one more
thing which many people have a question in their mind
that how much percentage do we get in the bike,
okay, how much percentage do we get in the claim?  If you
get it, it depends on
what is the future of your bike and whatever your bike is, it
means which insurance you have taken
and from which company,
all the companies have a different
process, there is a difference of 10-20%,
so you should also understand that the
insurance company
does not give you the entire money in it, you have to pay some money in it,
in some cases if you
die in an accident by chance etc., in that you get some money, that is a lot, that is
all the money,
but like you mean
in just damage insurance, that is if you are
giving a claim, then you will have to pay some percentage
from your pocket, like if
you are taking a claim for 100% damage, then the
company will give 70% in it and you will have to pay 30%, so this is how the
system is,
in this you will not have to give the entire money, so now I will
tell you
how will you get the money
of the insurance that you have, so the company takes the cheque or
cancelled cheque from you so that the
money can be transferred to your account  So
when your bike is parked for repair, then after
repair when you get it after 2 or 3
days, then whatever payment will be there, you will have to make it
from your pocket, whatever expenditure you incur, 200,
400, 5000, whatever expenditure is there in the bike,
you will have to make it from your pocket and
you will pay it only after that, when the
documents reach the company that
yes, you have done all the work, your bike is ok, then from
there the payment will be
processed in your account, which takes
around 10 to 15 days, it takes almost the same
time, the processing time in all the banks,
so I have told you all the basic details, I have
told you everything about
how you can claim insurance, there is a very
simple way to claim insurance, you will have to
take the documents of the person in whose name the bike is, Aadhar card,
PAN card and along with it your pollution and
insurance papers and
RC of the vehicle and driving license, you should have all these things in the name of the person in
whose name the bike is, only then
your insurance will be done  The
process will be done further and the
sooner your documents are complete, the
sooner your process will be done and if it is
from HDFC and ICICI then it is going to be done very
soon, so I have told you everything
in the video and I have
not made the video too long, I have told it quickly, if you
want the detailed video then you guys can comment,
you will get the detailed video as well, so let's go now, till then
bye bye, those who have
not seen the full detailed video of
insurance i.e. 5 year insurance, they can go and watch it, I will give you the link in billing and description in the i button, you guys can go and watch that video also, that is why I have told you for the knowledge that how to get
5 year insurance, so
you
guys should watch that video also and I have told you about the rest of the insurance in Hindi,
I have told you in Hindi, so I will
meet you in the next video, till then
bye bye
subscribe to the channel more and
like the video and also press the bell icon, keep
watching such latest videos